Finding Aid for the Jonathan Friedlander Collection of Middle Eastern Americana LSC.1314
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Stereographs, ca.1890s - 1908; 1 box (.5 linear feet)
  - Samaria T. W. Ingersoll., ca. 1904; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Holy Land series. Number 514. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - South side Mosque of Omar, showing detail of mosaics, Jerusalem T. W. Ingersoll., ca. 1904; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Holy Land series. Number 537. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Tomb of Eleazor and Phinhas, near Awertah T. W. Ingersoll., ca. 1904; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Holy Land series. Number 555. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Two women grinding at the mill, Jerusalem T. W. Ingersoll., ca. 1904; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Holy Land series. Number 543. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Vineyards, terraced hillside road to Bethlehem, Palestine T. W. Ingersoll., ca. 1904; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Holy Land series. Number 553. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Ancient mosques and tombs of the Mamelukes, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1376. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Arab masons building with sun dried brick, old Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 834.
  - Avenue of the Sphinxes from the first pylon, Karnak, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1391. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Bardoi Vila [sp.], from Gov. Summer Palace, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 879. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Bardoi Vila [sp.], from Gov. Summer Palace, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 879.
  - Beautiful Obelisk of Thumosis III at Karnak, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph, 2 copies (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1381. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Beggar woman on steps of Algerian street unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 898.
  - Characteristic street scene in modern city of Luxor, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph, 2 copies (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1387. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Colossal statues in the Temple of Rameses III at Karnak, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1374. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - David's judgment seat, Jerusalem unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 88.
  - Donkey carrying water skin, old Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 7.
  - Down the grand drawing room, Gov. Winter Palace, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 33.
  - Down the grand drawing room, Gov. Winter Palace, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 233. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Ecce Homo Arch, Jerusalem, Palestine unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 32.
  - Egyptian cemetery, old archways and tombs of the Khalifs, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 886.
  - Filling water skins and jars on the banks of the Nile at Luxor, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph, 2 copies (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1385. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - General view of the Temple of Sethos I at Karnak, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1383. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Glimpse of a typical Egyptian village, upper Nile unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph, 2 copies (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1390. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Glimpse of the rugged and desolate Libyan desert near Thebes, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1384. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Group of Arab guides and venders [sp.] at the pyramids, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1377. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Group of children in narrow street, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 55.
  - Howling dervishes in court of Mosque Gamaa El Ain / Mosque Sultan Hasan, from Citadel walls, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 2 halftone prints on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 151 and 152. Stereographic images printed on recto and verso.
  - Manger where Christ was born, as it is today unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 20. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Moorish building, near Gov. Palace city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 80.
  - Moorish building, near Gov. Palace, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 280. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Ocean front approach and mosque in distance, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph, 2 copies (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 835.
  - Plowing with Egyptian cattle and primitive plow, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 811.
  - Plowing with Egyptian cattle and primitive plow, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 811. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Public market, near Ghizeh Bridge, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph, 3 copies (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 826.
  - Pyramids at Ghizeh from the tramway, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1379. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Ruins of Bely Castle, city of Algiers, Algeria unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 807. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Sphinx and Pyramid, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 83
  - Statues of King Usertesen, Twelfth Dynasty, in museum at Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1375. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Street barber plying his trade in the streets of old Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1388. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Street lunch counter, old Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 853.
  - Street lunch counter, old Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 853. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Street scene, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 50.
  - Tombs of the Khalifs, across Egyptian cemetery, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 76.
  - Tombs of the Khalifs, across Egyptian cemetery, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 276. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Tourists on camels viewing Sphinx and pyramids, Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 830.
  - Typical group of Bisharins, upper Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 1382. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Via Dolorosa, near view of the arches, Jerusalem, Palestine unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 239. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Via Dolorosa, near view of the arches, Jerusalem, Palestine unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 39.
  - Water seller in the streets of old Cairo, Egypt unknown., undated; 1 halftone print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Number 831.
  - Arab village of reed mats and round fort on lower Euphrates Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., unknown; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number V27703 T. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Aswan Dam across the Nile, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8665 and 47. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Bird's-eye view of Beirut, Syria Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 492 (11151 in parentheses). Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Boats of the Nile, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8647 and 29. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Bringing water from the Nile, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8648 and 30. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Carmel [sp.] caravan, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8656 and 38. Title on verso reads "Camel caravan, Egypt." Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Cataract in the Nile – high water – Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8663 and 45. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Cataract in the Nile – low water – Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8664 and 46. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Church of the Holy Sepulchre, Jerusalem, Palestine Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1899; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 11000 (11 on verso). Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Date palm garden, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8650 and 32. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Drawing water from the Nile at low water Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number V9858 and 43. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Famous Galata Bridge and the golden horn, Constantinople, Turkey Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 10953 (41 and 22 on verso). Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Flooded date garden, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8666 and 48. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Garden of Gethsemane and Mount of Olives, Palestine Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 11002 (43 and 23 on verso). Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Gate of St. Stephen, from outside, Jerusalem, Palestine Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 11003 (19 on verso). Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Herding sheep near the Nile, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8652 and 34. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Homes in an oasis town, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8659 and 41. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Homes of the nomads, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number W8657 and 39. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Irrigating a field by means of a shadoof, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8651 and 33. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Looking across Cairo, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number V8644 and 26. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Making clay bricks, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number V8654 and 36. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Market place on an oasis, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8662 and 44. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Mosque of Mohammed Ali interior, Cairo, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1899; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 9788 (49 and 25 on verso). Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Over the roofs, "the street called straight," Damascus, Syria Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 493 (7323 in parentheses). Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Plowing with oxen, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8649 and 31. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Pyramid and the desert, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number V8646 and 28. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Sheep and goats in the desert, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number V8658 and 40. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Street scene in Cairo, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8645 and 27. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - View of Jerusalem from Mount of Olives, Palestine Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1906; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 7304 (44 on verso). Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - View over the Nile valley, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number V8655 and 37. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Washer women along the Nile, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number W8668 and 50. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Water carriers along the Nile, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number W8667 and 49. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - Well in an oasis, Egypt Meadville, PA: Keystone View Company., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Number 8660 and 42. Geography Units Series. Includes explanatory text on verso.
  - A "ship of the desert" passing tombs of bygone Moslem rulers outside east wall of Cairo, Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1896; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 5. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Bethlehem of Judea, the birthplace of Jesus, Palestine New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1906; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 8988 (34 in parentheses). Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Brick store-chambers of Pithom, the city built by Hebrew bondsmen (looking north) – Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1904; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 32. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Cairo, looking S.W. across city to pyramids that furnished stone for many of its buildings, Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1897; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 4. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Dancing girls in the harem New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1901; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Comic depiction features European man with women in Arab dress. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations on verso.
  - Favorite of the harem New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1901; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Garden of Gethsemene and Mount of Olives, from the eastern wall, Jerusalem, Palestine New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1903; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 8987 (33 in parentheses). Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Gathering tares from wheat, in the stony fields of Bethel, Palestine (looking south) New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 3. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations on verso.
  - Holy carpet parade with the Mahmal, before the departure of the pilgrims for Mecca – Cairo, Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1903; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 8. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Looking down (N. E.) upon the island of Philae and its temples from the island of Bigeh – Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1904; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 90. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Nilometer (measurer of inundations), Island of Elephantine, first cataract. Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1904; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 86. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Philae, the "pearl of Egypt," the templed island now doomed to destruction (view S.), Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1902; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 2606 (89 in parentheses). Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Plowing in the fertile plain of Sharon, Lydda, Palestine New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1900; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 3242 (27 in parentheses). Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations on verso.
  - Sixty-five foot portrait statues of Ramses II, before rock hewn temple of Abu Simbel, Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1904; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 95. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Tombs of the prophets, in the King's Dale, valley of Kedron, Jerusalem, Palestine New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1902; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 3095 (16 in parentheses). Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Valley of Kedron and village of Siloam, Palestine New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1896; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 3093 (14 in parentheses). Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.
  - Winnowing of the grain after the threshing – field work of peasant laborers – Egypt New York, NY: Underwood and Underwood., ca. 1904; 1 photographic print on stereo card: stereograph (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Number 38. Copyright by Underwood and Underwood. Includes title translations and explanatory text on verso.